hey guys there's this interesting
property of logarithms where you can
take this exponent and bring it to the
front it's something I think most people
tend to memorize but it feels kind of
weird doesn't it I wanted to see if we
can figure out why we can do it this is
a really nice animation here but
typically in books it looks more like
this on one side of the equation the a
is in front on the other side of the
equation the a is the exponent so we're
going to find this equation first let's
talk about log form versus exponential
form both of these equations mean the
exact same thing B the Y = X is the same
thing as y = log base B of X and this
will always be true the base of the
exponent will always be the base of the
logarithm and the exponent will always
be the thing that the logarithm is equal
to and the thing that the exponent is
equal to will always be the argument of
the logarithm and here's some colorcoded
circles to help us remember let's copy
down both of these equivalent equations
and I want to play around with them a
little bit first let's do this one b y =
x let's exponentiate both sides of the
equation to the power of a on the left
hand side these exponents will multiply
so we have B to the power of y * a and
we can change the order to get B to the
a * Y and then on the right hand side
this will be x to the A and now we're
back in exponent form let's identify
these three parts again and let's
rewrite this in logarithmic form this
green circle will be a y the base of the
logarithm will be B and the argument of
the logarithm will be x to the A and
this looks important let's put a box
around it and then let's go down to our
yal log base B of X I'm thinking we
should multiply both sides of this by a
on the left hand side we'll have a * Y
and on the right hand side we'll have a
* log Bas B of X this also looks
important let's put a box around it now
let's compare our two boxes since this
and this are both equal to a y we can
set them equal to each other so now we
have a * log Bas B of X is equal to log
base B of x to the A and that's what we
trying to find and here's all the work
right here how exciting